hafen-hamburg.de 2019-04-18

# Port of Hamburg | Privacy Policy

### Responsible organization:

Hafen Hamburg Marketing e.V., Pickhuben 6, 20457 Hamburg  
Phone: +49 40 37709 0  
Authorised representatives  
Axel Mattern und Ingo Egloff  
E-Mail: info@hafen-hamburg.de

### Chief privacy officer:

Andreas Kortmann netCo.privacy GmbH Reimerstwiete 11

20457 Hamburg  
Telefon: 040 540 90 90-0

E-Mail: [datenschutz@hafen-hamburg.de](mailto:datenschutz@hafen-hamburg.de)

Data protection is an important issue for Port of Hamburg Marketing (HHM). HHM respects and maintains the right of users and third parties to informational self-determination. The right for information self-determination is an essential component of the company philosophy of Port of Hamburg Marketing. We provide details below of the purpose, type and extent of collection and the use of personal data. Personal details are particulars on personal and factual circumstances of a particular or identified person.

### Selection and processing of personal and log data

When you visit our website we collect, process and use data: Personal data cannot always be eliminated from this process. Without this, use of our website on your terminal is only possible to a limited extent. But first we would like to state: HHM does not store users' IP addresses on the server, except for members of HHM who log in, using their personal data, to the internal area of PORTblog. Here IP addresses used to register for an event are temporarily stored to facilitate contract processing and security. Immediately after the event they are deleted.  
When visiting our site every time information is called up our web server collects protocol information on these processes:

  * Browser type/version
  * Operating system used
  * Referrer URL (last visited site)
  * Hostname of the relevant computer (IP address)
  * Time of server enquiry

All this data is evaluated anonymously for statistical purposes. It is not passed on to a third party. We do not link this data with other data. After statistical evaluation the data is regularly deleted within a week.

### PORTblog Registration system

HHM members can register to use PORTblog, which is a communication system used to register attendance at events. The following personal user data will be stored:

  * email address
  * password
  * IP address

For event registrations the event booked, the name of the attendee and, if appropriate the hotel booking are stored. In certain circumstances personal data for events will be made available to third parties.

### Use of customer data / deletion

If a company cancels its membership of HHM or an individual leaves a member company then the account on the PORTblog platform is deleted and the personal data for that individual is deleted, unless it is stored as a result of misuse or law enforcement purposes.

### Cookies

Use of the web site www.hafen-hamburg.de involves storing cookies on your terminal. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your hard disk. Cookie information can be used during your stay on the site to identify you as the authorised user. When cookies are installed, user IDs are given, but programmes are never run on the user’s computer. You can restrict cookie installation in your browser. But we must point out that the use of our website would then only be possible to a limited extent.

### Newsletter

If you would like to receive the newsletter offered by HHM, we need an email address as well as information allowing us to check that you are the owner of the email address given or that the owner is in agreement with receiving the newsletter. After registering for the Newsletter you will receive a confirmation email, which for you own security has to be re-confirmed. Your consent to storage of data, your email address as well as its use to send the Newsletter, can be cancelled at any time without explanation. This data is then deleted, unless it is needed for contractual or legal requirements. Cancelling the declaration of consent can be carried out by sending an email to info@hafen-hamburg.de, or by confirming the unsubscribe link in the Newsletter.

### Data security

Technical and organisation measures are taken to ensure that the regulations on data protection are observed by us and by our service providers.

### Notes for Internet communication

Transmission of online forms used in HHM's Internet offering and emails are encoded.

### Using the Twitter buttons

This offering uses the Twitter service buttons (plugins).  These buttons are offered by Twitter Inc. 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. They can be recognised by the terms 'Twitter ' or 'Follow' marked with a stylized blue bird. These buttons make it possible to share a comment or a page in Twitter or to follow a Twitter provider.

 When a user calls up a page on this Internet site, which has such a button, the browser builds a direct link to the Twitter server. The content of the Twitter button is transmitted directly from Twitter to the user's browser. Therefore HHM has no influence on the data that Twitter collects using this plugin. HHM only collects information on the user's IP address, the URL from sites visited.  
Further information on the data privacy statement can be found on Twitter:  http://twitter.com/privacy.

### Contact form

You can send your enquiry to HHM using the contact form. Your data - last name, first name and email address - and your question will be forwarded to us, answered and then deleted, unless it is needed to comply with legal requirements. The data will not be used for any other purpose or transmitted to a third party.

### etracker web analysis tool

On this website etracker technology - www.etracker.com will collect and store data for market optimization. From this data a pseudonym user profile can be created. Cookies can be used for this purpose. Cookies are small text files, which are stored in the visitor's local browser cache. Cookies enable Internet browsers to recognise features of websites the next time they are visited.  Data collected by etracker technology is not used to identify the visitor without their explicit consent, and is not merged with personal data of the bearer of the pseudonym. Data collection and storage can be disputed at any time with effect for the future.

### Data deletion

You can request deletion of your personal data at any time. In the event of deletion your personal data will be deleted, unless the data is required to fulfil contractual commitments or for legal purposes.

### Right to information/data protection officer/right to cancel

You have the right, at any time, to information, free of charge, on your personal data stored, the origin, receiver as well as the purpose of data processing. If you have questions on the processing of your personal data, or data protection in general, or would like to withdraw your consent to storage of your data, or to delete please contact info@hafen-hamburg.de. This also applies to answer requests for information, ideas or feedback.  
In line with the German Federal Data Protection Act you have the right to receive information, free of charge, on your personal data and if applicable the right to correct, block or delete this data.

### Changes to the data protection statement

HHM has the right to change this data protection statement at any time in line with valid data regulations. Therefore, we advise you to read through the statement from time to time. 

### Scope of the data protection statement

The data protection statement is only valid for content on our servers.

### Availability of the data protection statement

The data protection statement can be called up and printed out from the data protection link present on every page of the HHM website.
